Guide to the Charles Garside Jr. papers, 1953-1987 MS 421
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series II: Subject Files, 178330
  These are general Reformation/Rnaissance subject files apparently for use as needed and not intended for use with any specific course. These files contain primarily handwritten or typed lecture notes with some reprint material.
  - 16th Century Church Reform Readings, n.d.; 178454 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 16th Century German Religion, n.d.; 178455 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 16th Century Studies Conference, 1975; 178456 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The Ainsworth Psalter, n.d.; 178457 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Alexander Yablonsky - Captured by the Word of God, 1966; 178458 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Analysis of Luther's Letters to Buchholzer, n.d.; 178459 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Answer to Bishop Hugo, n.d.; 178460 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The Assault on Rome (1520), n.d.; 178461 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Augustine: Musical Texts by Garside, n.d.; 178462 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Avicenna in the West, n.d.; 178463 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Baumer: Seminar, n.d.; 178464 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Barraclough - Factors in German History, n.d.; 178465 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Basil, n.d.; 178466 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Berquin with Garside Edits, n.d.; 178467 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Biblical Authority in Luther & Calvin Readings & Notes, n.d.; 178468 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Blankenburg - Calvin, n.d.; 178469 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Becker - La Musique en Suisse, n.d.; 178470 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - The Birth of Opera, n.d.; 178471 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Brenz - Sermon on Music with Garside Notes, n.d.; 178472 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Bucer on Images, n.d.; 178473 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Calderwood - History of the Kirk of Scotland, 178474 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Calvin as a Musical Reformer, n.d.; 178475 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Calvin's First Psalter (1539), n.d.; 178476 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Coluccio Salutati Translation, n.d.; 178477 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Concept Maps, n.d.; 178478 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Conrad Celtis, n.d.; 178479 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Catholic Reform & the Counter-Reformation: The Resources of the Catholic Church, n.d.; 178480 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - The Church & the Greek World (1300-1500), n.d.; 178481 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Church & States in Zurich Before 1519, n.d.; 178482 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - The Christianismi Restitutio Notes, n.d.; 178483 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Cipolla Notes on Evolution of Society, n.d.; 178742 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - C.S. Smith Manuscripts, n.d.; 178743 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - The Czech Reformation, n.d.; 178744 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - "David" Handout, 178745 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - A Decade of Crisis, n.d.; 178746 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - In Defense of Place, 178747 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Dilthey, n.d.; 178748 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - The Dutch Psalter, n.d.; 178749 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Egli: Finished, n.d.; 178750 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - The Emergence of Nominalism, n.d.; 178751 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Erasmianism, n.d.; 178752 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Farner: Notes, n.d.; 178753 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Ficino & the Hermetic Literature Notes, n.d.; 178754 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - The Fifth Lutheran Council (1512-1517), n.d.; 178755 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - The First Welsh Psalter, n.d.; 178756 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Francesco Petrarcha, 1966; 178757 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Francis Bacon, n.d.; 178758 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - French Psalter of 1562, n.d.; 178759 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - French Refugees to Geneva (1548-1560) Handout, 178760 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - The French Revolution, n.d.; 178761 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Joachim Stieber - A Bibliographical Essay in Northern Humanism, 1964; 178762 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - John Geerken - The Historiography of Renaissance Religion, 1961; 178763 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Geneva: The Deacons, n.d.; 178764 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Geneva: Printing, n.d.; 178765 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - The German Text of Hoatzer, n.d.; 178766 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Giles of Viterbo Article Notes, n.d.; 178767 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Giovanni Pico Della Mirandola Notes, 178768 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Gordon Rupp - Joachim Vadianus (1484-1551), n.d.; 178769 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - The Gregorian Reform I & II, n.d.; 178770 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Gregory the Great & Saint Bonaventura, n.d.; 178771 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Hans Baron & the Crisis, n.d.; 178772 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Hans Freiherr von Campenhausen - Zwingli & Luther on the Question of Pictures, n.d.; 178773 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Harold Grimm - Lazarus Spengler (1479-1534) with Edits by Garside, n.d.; 178774 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Huldrych Zwingli, n.d.; 178775 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Humanism: Erasmus, n.d.; 178776 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Humanism & Mysticism, n.d.; 178777 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - The Iconoclasm in Basil of 1528 & 1529 Paper & Photocopies, n.d.; 178778 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Ignatius Loyola & the Jesuits, n.d.; 178779 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Ignatius Notes, n.d.; 178780 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Images Notes, n.d.; 178781 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - The Imperial Colloquies, n.d.; 178782 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Joachimsen, n.d.; 178783 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Johannes Kollwitz - The Picture & Picture Theology in the Middle Ages, n.d.; 178784 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - John Burcher Letters to Heinrich Bullinger, n.d.; 178785 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - John Calvin: The Humanist, n.d.; 178786 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Karlstadt: Images Essay & Book, n.d.; 178787 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Karstadt: Theses, n.d.; 178788 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Laity in the Ancient Church, n.d.; 178789 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Lehfeldt on Luther Notes, n.d.; 178790 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Lavater Notecards, Notes, & Readings, n.d.; 178791 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Leiturgia, n.d.; 178792 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Lenselink, n.d.; 178793 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Letter to Sadoleto, n.d.; 178794 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Lewis Lapham Letters & Poems, n.d.; 178795 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Luther, Calvin, & Erasmus on Images, n.d.; 178796 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Lufeure's Thought, n.d.; 178797 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - The Lutheran Concept of the Church, 1969; 178798 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Luther Experience Readings & Notes, n.d.; 178799 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Luther & the False Brethren; Luther & the Two Kingdoms Excerpts & Notes, n.d.; 178800 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Lydecker: Papers, n.d.; 178801 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Martin Luther, n.d.; 178802 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Martin Luther on Salvation by Faith Alone Handout, 178803 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - The Medieval Church, n.d.; 178804 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Medinger: Seminar Paper, n.d.; 178806 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Metrical Psalters, n.d.; 178807 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Miriam Chrisman Correspondence & Translations, 1965; 178808 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Miriam Chrisman's Manuscript CH I, n.d.; 178809 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Molanus Translations, 1960; 178810 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Muentzer: Prefaces, n.d.; 178811 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Music in the Work of Calvin, n.d.; 178812 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Mysticism & the Devotio Moderna, n.d.; 178813 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - The National Church, n.d.; 178814 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - North Italian History & Florence Notes, n.d.; 178815 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Quellenhefte - English Translation, n.d.; 178816 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Paul Kristeller - Eramus from an Italian Perspective, n.d.; 178817 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - The Peasant War & Thomas Muentzer, n.d.; 178818 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Pfister Notecards, n.d.; 178819 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Political Background: A Decade of Crisis, 178820 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Popular Piety, n.d.; 178821 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Preconditions for Humanism Notes, 178822 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - The Problem of Authority: The Papacy & Canon Law, n.d.; 178823 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Raphael Egli Letter to Chrstian Reader Translations, n.d.; 178824 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - The Reformation & the Arts, 1969; 178825 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Reformation & Education, n.d.; 178826 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - The Reformation: An Interpretation, 1969; 178827 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - The Reformation & Political Thought, n.d.; 178828 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - The Reformation Today, 1969; 178829 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Reformed Churches in 16th Century France Handout, 178830 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - A Refugee from the Netherlands: David Joris Annotated, 178831 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - The Reformation & the Imperial Crisis, n.d.; 178832 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Religion in the Renaissance Course Planning & Offprints, n.d.; 178833 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - The Renaissance Papacy (1420-1527), n.d.; 178834 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Report on Church Singing Raphael Egli, n.d.; 178835 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - The Revival of Greek in the Italian Renaissance, 1975; 178805 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Richard Terry - A Forgotten Psalter & Other Essays, n.d.; 178836 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - The Rise of the German Monarcy Notes, n.d.; 178837 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - The Rise of Toleration, 1969; 178838 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Robert Stevenson - Reformed Church Music, n.d.; 178839 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Rudolph Koch on Images, n.d.; 178840 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Schlussreden: 26, 33, n.d.; 178841 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - The Schmalkaldic League & the Religious Peace of Augsburg, n.d.; 178842 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - The Scottish Psalter, n.d.; 178843 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - The Scottish Psalter of 1635, n.d.; 178844 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Schlink, n.d.; 178845 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Schmidt-Clausing Notes, n.d.; 178846 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Schweizer: Abendmalsgestatung, 1953; 178847 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - The Second Zurich Disputation - 1st Draft, 178848 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Secularization Notes, n.d.; 178849 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The Seminar #4: Geneva, n.d.; 178850 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Servetus, n.d.; 178851 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Sohngen Drafts, 178852 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - The Souterliedekens, n.d.; 178853 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Spiritual Exercises, n.d.; 178854 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Steven Ozment - The Appeal of Protestant Ideas, n.d.; 178855 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - The Structure of Anabaptist Thought & its Relation to Luther & Zwingli, n.d.; 178856 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Theodore Beza - The Rights of Rulers, n.d.; 178857 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The Three Divisions, n.d.; 178858 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Three Lectures on the Organization of Learning, n.d.; 178859 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Timothy George - Calvin, Farel, & the Anabaptists, n.d.; 178860 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Totalitarianism II The Nazi Experience, n.d.; 178861 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Train Station Timeline, n.d.; 178862 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Trent: Images, n.d.; 178863 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Unification of Germany, n.d.; 178864 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Utopia & Geneva, n.d.; 178865 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Various Translated Papers on Zwingli, Bullinger, & "Tacitus in German Humanism", n.d.; 178866 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - The VCP & the Missions to France, n.d.; 178867 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Walter Bense - Noel Beda, Missing Link, n.d.; 178868 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Walter Kohler - The German Idea of Emperor at the Beginning of the 16th Century, n.d.; 178869 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Walton on Zurich, n.d.; 178870 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - From Wittenberg to Leipzig to Wartburg, n.d.; 178871 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Zurich - The Anabaptists & Spiritualism, n.d.; 178872 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Zwingli: Apologia with Edits, n.d.; 178873 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Zurich Before Zwingli Notes, n.d.; 178874 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Zwingli: A Brief Christian Introduction with Translation, n.d.; 178875 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Zwingli's Communique's on Mass & Images, n.d.; 178876 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Zwingli: Images (ABCI), n.d.; 178877 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Zwingli's Multi-Voice Composition, n.d.; 178878 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Zwingli to Oswald Myeonius, n.d.; 178879 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Zwingli's Picture, n.d.; 178880 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Zwingli-Texts: Music, n.d.; 178881 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Zwinglion Influence on Elizabethan Settlement, n.d.; 178882 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Series III: Scholarly Papers, 26914
  Material present may include some or all of the following: notes, drafts, final copies, invitations, reviews and correspondence.
  - Amherst Guest Lecture on Charles V, 1966; 178883 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Annotated Bibliography Draft, n.d.; 178884 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - "Archiv for Reformationsgeschicte", 1955; 178885 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - ART 401 Princeton Class Notes, 1949; 178886 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Assorted Travel & Research Notes, n.d.; 178931 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - "The Attitudes of Major Reformers Toward Music", 1962; 178932 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - "Some Attitudes of the Major Reformers Toward the Role of Music in the Liturgy", 1967; 178933 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Baumer: History 59 Lectures, 1951-1954; 178934 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Bibliographies, n.d.; 178935 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Book Reviews & Correspondence, 1986-1987; 178936 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Book Reviews & Correspondence on John Clavin, 1963-1968; 178937 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - De Fructu Book Review, 1968; 178938 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Book Reviews & Correspondence, 1976-1982; 178939 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Calvin Biography Research Inquiries, 1952-1973; 178940 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Calvin's Humanism Paper, n.d.; 178941 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - "Calvin: A Man & his Work" Manuscript Review, 1983; 178942 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - "Calvinism as Renaissance Artifact", 178943 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Case Studies & Essays, n.d.; 178944 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Charles V SFA University Guest Lecture, Nov. 14, 1973; 178945 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "The Continental Reformation", 1958; 178946 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Essays & Papers with Garside's Notes, n.d.; 178947 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Gardner Award Presentation, 1987; 178948 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "The Hackerman Year" Address to the Faculty Council, 1985; 178949 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - HIST 311 Princeton Class Notes, n.d.; 178950 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Gerald Straus Introduction, 1983; 178951 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Journal Articles & Notes, 1963-1971; 178952 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "La Farce Des Theologastres", 1974; 178953 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Leonardo da Vinci Short Course Talk, 1981; 178954 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "The Lords of Limit" Essay & Footnotes, n.d.; 178955 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "Ludwig Haetzer's Pamphlet Against Images", 1961; 178956 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Luther Paper Draft, n.d.; 178957 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Mediaeval Europe: Bibliography, n.d.; 178958 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Misc. Essays, Unknown Authors, n.d.; 178959 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - "The New England Mind", 1954; 178960 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - The Origins of Calvin's Theology of Music Correspondence, 1977-1979; 178961 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - The Origins of Calvin's Theology of Music Galley Proofs, n.d.; 178962 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - The Origins of Calvin's Theology of Music Monograph, 1979; 178963 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - The Origins of Calvin's Theology of Music Page Proofs, n.d.; 178964 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Patterns of Protestant Church Music Book Review, n.d.; 178965 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Perspectives on the Reformation, 1976; 178966 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Personal Lecture Notes, 1976; 178967 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Reformation Perspectives: Business Correspondence, 1968-1970; 178968 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - "The Reformation & the Visual Arts", n.d.; 178969 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - The Reformers on Music Article & Correspondence, 1967; 178970 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - "Renaissance Italy: The Shape of Leonardo's World, Jan 1982; 178971 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Renaissance Reformation Resurgence Colloquium on Calvin Papers, 1976; 178972 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Response to Bauwsma, 1984; 178973 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Restitution Dissent & Renewal Conference Correspondence, 1974-1975; 178974 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Restitution, Dissent, & Renewal Conference Papers & Pamphlets, 1975; 178975 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Reviews & Correspondence, 1958-1964; 178976 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Richard Isenberg Memorial Speech & Trip Information, n.d.; 178977 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Societe Francaise des Seiziemistes, 1979; 178978 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Sermons & Prayers, ca 1960; 178979 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - "The Three Gifts of Christmas", 1966; 178980 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - University of Virginia Address, 1970; 178981 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Zwingli & the Arts Correspondence, 1961-1967; 178982 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Zwingli & the Arts Publication Correspondence, Contract, & Royalties, 1963-1980; 178983 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Zwingli & the Arts Reviews, n.d.; 178984 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Series IV: Academic Organizations, 178331
  Scope and Contents Notes
  Garside belonged to or worked with most of the scholarly organizations and societies relevant to his interest in the Reformation and the Renaissance. Notably: American Historical Association, Southern Historical Association, American Society for Reformation Research, American Philosophical Society, Houston Philosophical Society and the American Society of Church History. In addition to these organizations, there is correspondence and printed material present concerning institutions, such as the John Calvin Theological Seminary in Grand Rapids, Mich., which were of interest to Garside.
  - 2nd International Congress for Calvin Research Travel Plans & Expenses, 1978; 178891 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - 16th Century Studies Conference, 1975; 178892 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - American Historical Association Affiliated Societies Committee Correspondence, 1974; 178893 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - American Historical Association Annual & Semiannual Meetings, 1958-1960; 178894 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - American Historical Association Convention Programs, 1946-1972; 178895 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - American Historical Association Convention, 1960-1961; 178896 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - American Historical Association Joint Session Correspondence, 1971; 178897 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - American Historical Association Joint Session Papers, 1971; 178898 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - American Philosophical Society Grant Request, 1981; 178899 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - American Society of Church History Pamphlets & Correspondence, 1979; 178900 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - American Society of Church History & Reformation Research Correspondence, 1973-1975; 178901 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - American Society for Reformation Research & American Academy of Religion, 1974; 178902 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - American Society for Reformation Research Business Correspondence, 1973; 178903 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - American Society for Reformation Research Correspondence, 1975; 178904 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - American Society for Reformation Research Joint Session Text, n.d.; 178905 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - American Society for Reformation Research Membership, 1973; 178906 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - American Society for Reformation Research Program Correspondence, 1973-1974; 178907 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - American Society for Reformation Research Proposed Constitution, 1969; 178908 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Calvin Studies Society Colloquiums, 1976-1987; 178909 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Center for Reformation Research Director's Meeting & Notes, 1974; 178910 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence with Robert Leslie, 1960-1962; 178911 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Foundation for Reformation Research Programs, ca. 1960s; 178912 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Houston Philosophical Society Membership, 1978; 178913 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - International Conference on Calvin Research, Sept. 1978; 178914 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Translation Bills, n.d.; 178915 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Introduction Course in Western Civilization Creation & Correspondence, 1970-1972; 178916 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Joint American Society for Reformation Research & Church History Session Correspondence, 1973-1975; 178917 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - The Meeter Center for Calvin Studies, 1984; 178918 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - National Association of Independent Schools Conference, 1980; 178919 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - New England Renaissance Conference, 1965-1967; 178920 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Scholarly Correspondence, 1950-1959; 178921 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Scholarly Correspondence, 1960-1969; 178922 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Scholarly Correspondence, 1970-1979; 178923 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Scholarly Correspondence, 1980-1987; 178924 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Scholarly Correspondence, 178925 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Southern Historical Association Correspondence, 1966-1967; 178926 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Southern Historical Association Correspondence, 1971; 178927 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Southern Historical Association Correspondence, 1978-1979; 178928 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Southern Historical Association Program Papers, 1974; 178929 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Walter Bense Paper for American Society for Reformation Research, 1975; 178930 (Box 8, Folder 39)
- Series V: Rice-Related Papers, 27107
  This series contains materials relating to the Rice Residential College System, executive papers from Garside's time as Executive Associate of Baker, Matriculation Addresses, and History Department meeting minutes.
  - Alumni Association & Education Committee, 1973-1974; 178985 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Association of Rice Alumni Presentation, 1978-1980; 178986 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Baker Convocation Committee Planning, 1964-1965; 178987 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Baker College 15th Anniversary Dinner, 1972-1973; 178988 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Baker College Associates Night Invitations & Thank Yous, 1973-1979; 178989 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Baker College Correspondence & Newsletters, 1977-1979; 178990 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Baker College Course Correspondence & Syllabi, 1973-1979; 178991 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Baker College Course Correspondence & Syllabi, 1980-1981; 178992 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - The Coherent Minor Newsclippings & Correspondence, 1986-1987; 178993 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Department of History Meeting Minutes & Newsletters, 1982-1983; 178994 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Misc. Correspondence About the Rice College System, Community, & Courses, 1973-1987; 178995 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Reports to the President, 1980-1986; 178996 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Mellon Fellowship Search Applications, 1982; 178997 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "Only Connect" Rice Universtiy Matriculation Address, 1979; 178998 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Reports on the Residential College System at Rice, n.d.; 178999 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Rice Research Grants: Calvin Biography, 1979-1980; 179000 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Rice & Yale Dinner, Commencement, & Speaking Pamphlets, 1963-1976; 179001 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Preface to "Architecture at Rice", 1980; 179002 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - "The Vanished Tower" Rice University Matriculation Address, 1969; 179003 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Series VI: Personal Papers, 26899
  - Address Books & Address Notecards, n.d.; 179004 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Book Pages with Personal Inscriptions, 1948-1962; 179005 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Garside Teaching Excellence Newsclippings, 1979-1987; 179006 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Hotchkiss Class of 1959 Address Speech Notes, 179007 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Offprints with Personalized Inscriptions, n.d.; 179008 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1948-1959; 179009 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1960-1963; 179010 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Personal Correspondence Regarding Garside's Departure from Yale, 1965-1966; 179011 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1970-1979; 179012 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1980-1987; 179013 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Personal Correspondence - Garside's Open Letter Regarding his Health, Nov 1983; 179014 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Personal Correspondence Misc. (Photographs), 1960-1987; 179015 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Personal Papers & Documents, n.d.; 179016 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Poetry & Book Excerpts, n.d.; 179017 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Recipes, n.d.; 179018 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Recommendation Thank You Notes, 1966-1987; 179019 (Box 9, Folder 35)
- Series VII: Media, 178332